

Project Management Team Professional with 15 years of experience in oil & gas industries (upstream and downstream). A team player who demonstrate skills in planning and control, interface and resource Honest, integrity, and having strong interpersonal skills: proven ability to work well with individuals at all levels management in order to achieve project deliverables within the constraints of cost, time and performance.

JANI SUMITRO PARDOSI

Contact

Name : Jani Sumitro Pardosi
Date of Birth : 27 Agustus 1980
Martial Status : Married
Nationality : Indonesian
Language : Indonesian, English

Mobile No : +6282180562791

E-Mail : janisumitro8031@gmail.com janisumitro@yahoo.com

Training

- Basic First Aid and Firefighting Training
- Man Management
- Achievement Motivation
- Project Management

Education

Bachelor degree, Sumatera Utara University

Experience

> PT. Bojonegoro Bangun Sarana (PT. BBS)

Assignment : JTB Unitization Gas Project, Bojonegoro East Java

Period : Maret 2021 – Present
Position Held : Project Manager

Duties and Responsibility:

- 1. Manage the relationship with the client and all stakeholders.
- 2. Establish and maintain relationships with third parties/vendors.
- 3. Assist in the definition of project scope and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility
- 4. Develop a detailed project plan to monitor and track progress
- 5. Strong interpersonal and communication skills
- 6. Report and escalate to management as needed.

> Rapid Infrastruktur Indonesia

Assignment : Batik Project Sugar Plant, Waingapu NTT

Period : July 2020 – February 2021
Position Held : Construction Manager

Duties and Responsibility :

- 1. Plan ahead to prevent problems and resolve any emerging ones.
- 2. Review the work progress on daily basis.
- 3. Select tools, materials and equipment and track inventory
- 4. Develop a detailed project plan to monitor and track progress
- 5. Strong interpersonal and communication skills
- Track project performance, specifically to analyze the successful completion of short and long-term goals.

Rapid Infrastruktur Indonesia

Assignment : Tangguh Expansion Project (TEP) Train 3, BP Project Papua

Period : September 2019 – June 2020 Position Held : Construction Manager

Duties and Responsibility :

- 1. Plan ahead to prevent problems and resolve any emerging ones.
- 2. Review the work progress on daily basis.
- 3. Select tools, materials and equipment and track inventory
- 4. Develop a detailed project plan to monitor and track progress
- 5. Strong interpersonal and communication skills
- 6. Perform risk management to minimize project risks
- Track project performance, specifically to analyze the successful completion of short and long-term goals.

➤ PT. Timas Suplindo EPCI

Assignment : TDAE Processing Plant Project, ENERCO Project Batam

Period : October 2018 - August 2019

Position Held : Site Manager

Duties and Responsibility :

- Supervising and overseeing the direction of the project (or a package), ensuring that the client's specifications and requirements are met, reviewing progress and
- Coordinating and supervising construction workers
- 3. Selecting tools and materials
- 4. Checking and preparing site reports, designs and drawings
- Plan, organize, control, and evaluate construction projects

Experience

> PT. Timas Suplindo EPCI

Assignment : Decoupling Project, RAPP Project, Pangkalan Kerinci Riau

Period : November 2017 - September 2018

Position Held : Site Manager

Duties and Responsibility :

- 1. Determines project schedule by studying project plan and specifications,
- 2. Review location of existing utilities for possible conflict and relocation.
- 3. Controls project plan by reviewing design, specifications, plan and schedule changes if require
- 4. Controls project costs by approving expenditures, administering contractor contracts.
- 5. Prepares project status reports by collecting, analyzing, and summarizing information and trends; recommending actions
- 6. Interface with Client and coordinate with other discipline
- 7. Provide design assistance to support engineer during construction phase including shop plan review

> PT. Timas Suplindo EPCI

Assignment : Modernization Jakarta Grease Plant Project, Pertamina Lubricant Project, Jakarta

Period : February 2014- August 2017

Position Held : Chief Engineer

Duties and Responsibility :

- Determines project schedule by studying project plan and specifications, calculating time requirements, sequencing project elements.
- 2. Review location of existing utilities for possible conflict and relocation.
- 3. Controls project plan by reviewing design, specifications, plan and schedule changes if require
- 4. Controls project costs by approving expenditures, administering contractor contracts.
- Prepares project status reports by collecting, analyzing, and summarizing information and trends; recommending actions.
- 6. Interface with Client and coordinate with other discipline
- 7. Provide design assistance to support engineer during construction phase including shop plan review

> PT. Timas Suplindo EPCI

Assignment : Pipeline Replacement XA Process Platform, Pertamina EP Indramayu

Period : Jun 2013 - Jan 2014
Position Held : Senior Project Engineer

Duties and Responsibility :

- 1. Coordinate all discipline Engineer to working the project
- 2. Making safety Inspection and ensuring construction and site safety
- 3. Review location of existing utilities for possible conflict and relocation.
- 4. Make sure the actual pipeline compatible to P& ID and Isometric
- 5. Interface with Client and coordinate with other discipline
- 6. Provide design assistance to support engineer during construction phase including shop plan review

> PT. Timas Suplindo EPCI

Assignment : Construction Project Vapor Evaporation

Period : Jan 2013- May 2013 Position Held : Project Engineer

Duties and Responsibility :

- 1. Monitoring compliance to applicable codes, practices, QA/QC policies, performance standards and specifications
- 2. Review location of existing utilities for possible conflict and relocation.
- Coordinate structural detail and design features within the project. Conducts meeting with designer and detailer as required
- 4. Interface with Client and coordinate with other discipline
- 5. Provide design assistance to resident engineer during construction phase including shop plan review

> PT. Timas Suplindo EPCI

Assignment : Construction 2 units Chloride Removal, Pertamina RU V, East Kalimantan

Period : Jan 2012 – Dec 2012 Position Held : Project Engineer

Duties and Responsibility:

- 1. Supervising and overseeing the direction of the project (or a package), ensuring that the client's specifications and requirements are met, reviewing progress and liaising with quantity surveyors to monitor costs.
- 2. Coordinating and supervising construction workers
- 3. Selecting tools and materials
- 4. Checking and preparing site reports, designs and drawings
- 5. Plan, organize, control, and evaluate construction projects

Experience

➤ PT. Timas Suplindo EPCI

Assignment : Fabrication and Installation Energy Plant, Mega Rimba Project, South Sumatra

Period : Jan 2011- Dec 2011 Position Held : Field Engineer

Duties and Responsibility :

1. Conduct and document facility performance test

- 2. Assist the construction superintendent with construction planning and record keeping
- 3. Travel off site to meetings with customers and vendors
- 4. Conduct electrical progress work inspections on continuous basis along with complete end electrical installations
- 5. Support project controls and supervise detailed work plans as well as mini-schedules establishment.
- 6. Obtain field measurement from which materials are ordered

> PT. Timas Suplindo EPCI

Assignment : Construction PLTU 3 X 315 MW, PLN Project Banten Province

Period : May 2009 – December 2010

Position Held : Field Engineer

Duties and Responsibility :

1. Conduct and document facility performance test

- 2. Travel off site to meetings with customers and vendors
- 3. Oversee and coordinate performance and routine activities of electrical field engineering personnel.
- 4. Direct and assist technically Electrical Superintendents and crafts.
- 5. Obtain field measurement from which materials are ordered

> PT. Kiani Lestari

Assignment : Paper Manufacturing/ Kiani Kertas, East Kalimantan

Period : November 2006 – April 2009

Position Held : Procurement

Duties and Responsibility :

- 1. Prepare Purchase orders and send copies to suppliers and to department originating requests.
- 2. Determine if inventory quantities are sufficient for needs, ordering more materials when necessary.
- ${\bf 3.} \quad \text{Respond to customer and supplier inquiries about order status, change or cancellation}$
- 4. Perform buying duties when necessary.
- Contact supplier in order to schedule or expedite deliveries and to resolve shortages, missed or late deliveries, and other problem
- 6. Review requisition orders in order to verify accuracy, and specification

I certify that this record is truthful

Jani Sumitro Pardosi